

Visual finesse and better experiences drive my work wagon. The challenge to play in the hybrid space, an infusion of design and technology is exciting and fulfilling. My specialities include Human Computer Interaction, Design Research, Data Visualisation, User Experience Design, and Story-boarding."

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Microsoft, IDC, Hyderabad, India

User Experience Design Intern, Jul 2017-Dec 2017

#### Freelance

Digital illustrations for educational game Monster Math. Branding for publishing startup Flying Penguin. Wall graffiti for cakeshop E=MC2.

#### Deloitte-USI, Bangalore, India

Business Analyst - Cyber Security, Jul 2014-Jul 2015

### General Electric, Bangalore, India

Software Developer Intern, Jan 2014-Jun 2014

## IBM, Bangalore, India

Software Developer Intern, Jul 2013-Aug 2013

# College Editorial Board MIT, Manipal, India

Creative Head of council of 40 students, 2013-2014

### **PUBLICATIONS**

"Community Based System Design for Indian Railways in the Context of Senior Citizens"

- Interact 2017, IIT-Bombay - Springer

"Introducing New Age To ICH: Revering Matters Of Significance" - IndiaHCl2016, IIT-Bombay - ACM

## **EDUCATION**

Hochschule für Technik und Wirtschaft, Berlin, Germany (Exchange Student) Communication Design, Winter 2017

National Institute of Design, Bangalore, India M.Des in Information Design, 2015-2017

Manipal Institute of Technology, MAHE, Manipal, India B.Tech in Computer Science, 2010-2014 | 8.6 CGPA

St. Michael's High School, Patna, India CBSE, 1998-2010 | XIIth 92%, Xth 95%

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

UXIndia 2017 - Student Gold Award

Adobe Design Achievement Awards 2017 - Semifinalist

Information is Beautiful Awards 2017 - Longlist

D'Vibes Deloitte Annual Fest 2015 - Best Logo

Microsoft Windows App Hackathon, Manipal, 2013 -Second Prize

Revels - Manipal Fest 2010-14 - Awards in Fine Arts & Cartooning

Techniche, IIT-G 2010 - School Student Shortlist

Best Michaelite, 2010 - Excellence for 12 years at school

# **GOOD AT**

Sketch

Principle Adobe XD

Photoshop

Illustrator

Flinto

Story-Boarding

HTML/CSS

Javascript

Prototyping

## **INTERESTS**

**User Experience** User Interface Design Research Information Architecture

Data Visualisation

Graphic Design

#### UX Graphics Illustrations HTML **CSS** Web JS Mobile UI Music Fiction\_/ Information Superhero Architecture Desserts Data Narrative

**SUMMING IT UP!** 

## **REACH OUT AT**

E: atul ku@nid.edu myspace.atul@gmail.com

P: +91 9742721604

W: www.atulkr.com linkedin.com/in/atul-kr be.net/\_atul\_kumar instagram.com/\_atul\_kumar